# Anna B. Kawiecki

PhD Epidemiology (expected 2022), UC Davis null

🖂 akawiecki@ucdavis.edu 📞 +1 (530) 760-7123 🗘 akawiecki

**SUMMARY OF PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE** I am a veterinarian training as a research epidemiologist with a focus on vector-borne diseases with a background that encompasses clinical, molecular and quantitative experience. I have extensive experience in conducting field work and managing data in large field-based research operations, performing molecular diagnostic work with arboviruses in both BSL-2 and BSL-3 conditions and with mosquito colony maintenance. Currently I am investigating arbovirus transmission dynamics by building statistical, mathematical and spatio-temporal models.

**EDUCATION** 

University of California, Davis, Ph.D. Epidemiology

expected 2022

Davis, California

Louisiana State University, M.Sc. Master in Veterinary and Biomedical Sciences

2017

Baton Rouge, Louisiana

Universidad Complutense de Madrid, D.V.M

2013

Madrid, Spain

**EMPLOYMENT** 

University of California, Davis, COVID-19 Case investigation

2021- present

as a **contact tracer** I gained experience collecting human data and communicating with stake-holders regarding COVID-19

University of California, Davis, Graduate Student Researcher

2018- present

Advisor: Dr. Christopher Barker

Davis, California

As a **researcher**, I am working on improving the measurement of vector control efficacy and the application of vector control interventions. I am currently modeling how the efficacy of ultra-low volume indoor insecticide spraying varies over space and time, to determine if this intervention has an effect on the vector density in neighboring areas and, if so, the duration of this effect.

University of California, Davis, Data Systems Analyst

2017-2018

Employer: Dr. Amy Morrison

Iquitos, Peru

I was a **data manager and analyst** for both a clinical vector control trial ("Spatial Repellents for Arbovirus Control"), a UC Davis-University of Notre Dame collaboration, and an NIH funded P01 grant ("Quantifying Heterogeneities in Dengue Transmission Dynamics") led by

1 1/4

Dr. Thomas Scott, based in Iquitos, Peru. I developed a mobile data collection application custom-made for this purpose and setting using CommCare, an application-building software, and was heavily involved in training and troubleshooting with our field teams to ensure the successful deployment of the app. I also maintained and improved a database of 15,000 human participants and over 100,000 mosquito samples using MySQL, PostreSQL, QGIS and R, and produced project reports that optimized the implementation of the field activities.

### Louisiana State University, Graduate Student Researcher

2014-2017

Advisor: Dr. Rebecca Christofferson

Baton Rouge, Louisiana

As a **researcher** I characterized the antibody response to Zika virus (ZIKV) and Dengue virus (DENV) in mice by:

-evaluating the effect of re-exposure to ZIKV on the neutralization and DENV-enhancement ability of ZIKV antibodies in C56BL/6 mice.

-characterizing the disease, viremia, pathology and antibody response caused by ZIKV in IRF3/7 DKO mice

I also evaluated the vector competence of local *Aedes aegypti* and *Aedes albopictus* mosquitoes to ZIKV and Chikungunya virus (CHIKV), developed and maintained laboratory colonies of field-caught *Aedes aegypti* and *Aedes albopictus*, and became adept at working in Biosafety Level 3 (BSL-3) environments, where most of my experiments took place.

Complutense University of Madrid, Undergraduate Student Researcher

2012-2014

Advisor: Gustavo Domínguez Bernal

Madrid, Spain

As an **undergraduate student researcher** I participated in the development of a vaccine against canine Leishmaniasis using an attenuated Salmonella strain as the infection vehicle of a plasmid containing Leishmania antigens into dendritic and macrophage cells.

TEA	CH	ING	EX	PFR	RIEN	JCE.

**Teaching Assistant:** Quantitative Epidemiology II (EPIDEM 203)

Winter 2020

#### CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

Small Animal Clinic Centro Veterinario Villalba IF, Externship	2012-2013
Experience in basic diagnostic procedures, anesthesiology and surgery	Madrid, Spain
Ruminant Clinic of the Complutense Animal Hospital, Internship	2011-2012
Experience in basic diagnostic procedures and anesthesiology	Madrid, Spain

\_\_\_\_\_

**GRANTS & AWARDS** 

Global Food Initiative Fellowship 2021–2022

3,000\$ U.C. Davis

Graduate Student Support Program, School of Veterinary Medicine 2020–2021

2 2/4

21,000\$		U.C. Davis
Pacific Southwest Center of Excellence in Vector-bo	orne Diseases fellowship	2019-2020
30,000\$		U.C. Davis
Graduate Student Support Program, School of Vete	erinary Medicine	2018–2019
21,000\$		U.C. Davis
Hannelore-Storz Travel Award		2016
500\$	Lousiar	na State University
Prize for Best Scientific Communication		2012
11th Congress of Veterinary and Biomedical Sci	ences Universidad Comp	lutense de Madrid
Erasmus Scholarship		2010-2011
One year study abroad program	Justus-Liebig Universität,	Giessen, Germany.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

**Kawiecki, AB** and Christofferson, R. C. "Zika-induced antibody response enhances dengue serotype 2 replication in vitro." *Journal of Infectious Diseases* 2016

**Kawiecki, AB**, Mayton EH, Dutuze MF, Goupil BA, Langohr IM, Del Piero F and Christofferson, R. C. "Tissue tropisms, infection kinetics, histologic lesions, and antibody response of the MR766 strain of Zika virus in a murine model". *Virology Journal* 2017.

Elson WH, Reiner RC, Siles C, Bazan I, Vilcarromero S, Riley-Powell AR, **Kawiecki AB**, et al. "Heterogeneity of Dengue Illness in Community-Based Prospective Study, Iquitos, Peru". *Emerging Infectious Diseases* 2020

#### **PRESENTATIONS**

**Kawiecki, A. B.**, Morrison A. C., Barker C. M., "Spatial analysis on the impact of Ultra-low Volume indoor insecticide spraying on Aedes aegypti household density" (Poster). GeoVet, Davis, California, USA, 2019

**Kawiecki A. B.**, Elson W.H.D., Donnelly M., Schwarz J., Simpson J. K., Barker C. M., Scott T. W., Achee N.L., Morrison A. C. "Use of mobile data collection tools to improve implementation of epidemiological trials in Iquitos, Peru". (Poster). American Society of tropical Medicine and Hygiene 67th Annual Meeting, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA, 2018

**Kawiecki, A. B.** and Christofferson, R. C.. "Boosting alters the cross-neutralizing capacity of antibody-response following Zika exposure in C57Bl/6 mice." (Oral). American Society of tropical Medicine and Hygiene 65th Annual Meeting, Atlanta, Georgia, USA, 2016

**Kawiecki, A. B.** and Mayton EH, Dutuze MF, Goupil BA, Langohr IM, Del Piero F and Christofferson, R. C. "Characterization of a murine model of Zika virus infection: histologic lesions and evidence of a role for epididymal epithelial cells in sexual transmission" (Poster). Phi Zeta Emphasis Day, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, USA, 2016

3

**Kawiecki, A.B.** "Vector competence for Arboviruses of Louisiana strains of Aedes mosquito species" (Oral). 57th Annual Meeting of the Louisiana Mosquito Control Association, Lake Charles, Louisiana, USA, 2015

**Kawiecki, A.** "Organochlorine Insecticides: Identification, Evaluation and Assessment of Risks" (Oral) [Spanish]. 12th Congress of Veterinary and Biomedical Sciences, Complutense University, Madrid, Spain, 2013

**Kawiecki, A.** "Food chain: alternatives from food sovereignty" (Oral) [Spanish]. 12th Congress of Veterinary and Biomedical Sciences, Complutense University, Madrid, Spain, 2013

**Kawiecki, A.** "Tendon retraction in young calves," (Oral) [Spanish]. 11th Congress of Veterinary and Biomedical Sciences, Complutense University, Madrid, Spain, 2012 Awarded a Prize for Best Scientific Communication.

**Kawiecki, A.** "Healing properties of honey," (Oral) [Spanish]. 11th Congress of Veterinary and Biomedical Sciences, Complutense University, Madrid, Spain, 2012

OUTREACH

## Girls in Outdoor Adventure in Leadership and Science (GOALS) Mentor

2018-2019

2019- present

GOALS is a student-led organization at U.C. Davis that promotes field-based science and leadership skills in femme-identifying high school students through a free, immersive two-week backpacking trip to the Sequoia and King's Canyon National Park. In addition to this trip, GOALS provides the participants with a one-on-one year-long mentoring program that participated in. This program is meant to work on the skills learned on the trip and help the participants with college applications and questions related to future careers in STEM.

## Davis Night Market

The Davis Night Market is a non-profit organization with the goal of reducing food insecurity, food waste, building community, and sustainability. It operates by recovering left-over food from local businesses in the city of Davis and distributing them freely at the central park. I am heavily involved in the operational, outreach and fund raising activities of this organization.

LANGUAGES

- -Spanish (fluent)
- -English (fluent)
- -Polish (fluent)
- -German (intermediate -B2)

4